hi there I want to introduce you to
something called the glass bead game
which is something I've been playing
quite a lot of recently it's a way of
generating ideas in a sort of playful
way in a sort of game space and I'll
just very briefly explain it in this
video here and then as I play games I
will start posting them in a new
playlist on the channel and yeah you can
watch them if you think they're fun and
my hope is that people will pick on and
pick up on it and start playing their
own glass bead games all over the place
because I think it's a really good way
of starting off a conversation and it's
a really good way of generating you know
a creative intelligence kind of thing so
it goes something like this
you can play with as many players as you
want you can play at any format you want
it can be in writing by video by phone
it can be by voice message it can pretty
much anything at all the idea is that
you choose a topic to start with and
then the first player takes their turn
and so that can be right a hundred words
or talk for one minute or make a
three-minute video or whatever right
just to keep it simple I'll imagine a
two-player game on video like this right
and so let's say that we agree at the
start of the game we're gonna play a
10-minute game so five one-minute turns
each in sequence I start and we pick the
topic of father and so I will speak for
one minute on anything that comes to my
mind related to father the idea is not
to rely too much on preconceived notions
right but just just just say whatever
comes to mind let it flow freely one of
the not really a rule but it's you know
you try to avoid talking from a place of
ego and so the personal pronouns i and
you are avoided as much as possible as
if it's a it's not the end of the world
right but but but to try and avoid the
idea being that you can then open up to
a larger space than just your own self
right that's that's the point of it so
yeah I speak for one minute I fill the
one minute and I stop and then you take
over for one minute and you have
been listening very intently and very
carefully to what I've been saying and
whatever comes up for you while I have
been speaking is what you try and
articulate if nothing comes up then
you're free to sit in silence or just
raise something of your own that has
nothing to do with anything I said but
is on your mind you know there's there's
no hard and fast rules here it's about
being present to what's going on in the
moment and to what's going on in
yourself and being responsive to what
the other is saying and trying to create
an interactive free-flowing
idea space that's that's the notion and
so backwards and forwards five tones
each at the end of ten minutes you stop
and then if you wish to continue the
conversation it's a really good starting
point right because ideas have come up
and then you think oh god I really want
to explore that a little bit further and
so it can be really excellent starting
point for a conversation expanding it
out a little bit if you've got a group
say ten people and again again there's a
myriad number of ways you can play
around with this but if you've got ten
people you could say split up into five
groups or to all discuss the same topic
come back into a group of ten and then
have a group discussion where you can
exchange the ideas that came up in your
little groups of two with each other so
it's it's a really fantastic starting
point for having interesting
illuminating and sometimes really
groundbreaking discussions where I can
do wow I had never thought of it in that
way before that's really like you know
opened up a whole new room of thought
for me so and that happens quite a lot
that happens quite a lot it's really
engaging really stimulating really fun
and really challenging so yeah I highly
recommend it and like I said I will post
some example games and in this playlist
following on from this video so as
always thank you so much for watching
and see you soon